dayoutwiththekids.co.uk 2019-08-25

# Privacy & Cookie Policy | Day Out With The Kids

At Day Out With The Kids, the privacy of our visitors is of extreme importance to us.

In order to provide you with the best possible service, we sometimes need to collect information about you. Day Out With The Kids Limited has a legitimate interest in processing such information for the reasons outlined below:

\- To provide our services, activities or online content, to provide you with information about them and to deal with your requests and enquiries 

\- To provide you with the most user-friendly online navigation experience

\- For "service administration purposes", which means that Day Out With The Kids may contact you for reasons related to the service, activity or online content you have signed up for (e.g. to provide you with password reminders, to notify you that a particular service, activity or online content has been suspended for maintenance, or to notify you of updates to our Privacy and Cookies Policy or Terms of Use.)

 This policy outlines how we treat your personal data after it has been collected by any of our channels which include our website, app, social media pages or any future digital services or channels as they evolve.

**Data Control**

Any personal information provided to us is controlled by Day Out With The Kids Limited, 3&4 Regal Court, 6 Sovereign Road, Kings Norton Business Centre, Birmingham, B30 3FJ.

**Collection Methods**

Day Out With The Kids may collect and process information about you at the point at which you interact with our products and services, as detailed below:

  * When you become a member of Day Out With The Kids
  * When you subscribe to our newsletter
  * When you complete a survey or enter a competition
  * When you download the app
  * When you leave a product review
  * When you follow us on our social media channels
  * When we use cookies to see which website pages are the most popular

We operate in accordance with data protection legislation.  If you have any questions about the information we hold on you or this privacy policy, please feel free to contact us by email at help@dayoutwiththekids.co.uk.

**Your Personal Information**

All personal information you provide us with such as name, address, email etc will be held securely and we will not sell, rent or trade your personal information to third parties unless you give permission to do so. Once a payment is processed we do not retain your credit card number, and any information we do retain is held in our secure database.

We also use your personal information to prevent or detect fraud or abuses of our website.

When you subscribe to our newsletter you consent to being sent news, information on products and special offers that we think may interest you. If you register with us you hereby grant permission for us to contact you in this way.

When you give us your personal information you consent to the collection, storage and processing of this information by Day Out With The Kids in accordance with this privacy policy. If you send us information, when appropriate we may use this as testimonials, but we will not display any personal information unless you have given prior consent. 

**Opt Out Policy**

Newsletter recipients can opt out of receiving further information from us at any time by emailing us at membership@dayoutwiththekids.co.uk.

**Change of Details**

To update any of your details such as email or address please email us at membership@dayoutwiththekids.co.uk.

**Membership cancellations**

Members of Day Out With The Kids can cancel their memberships at any point in line with the stipulations set out in the Membership Terms & Conditions. Please note, Day Out With The Kids may continue to contact you via newsletter following the cancellation of a membership to keep you up to date with new products & services, unless you specifically opt-out as per the instructions in our “Opt Out Policy” section above.

**Retention policy**

Day Out With The Kids retain all customer information for 4 years after they last interacted with us. Where there has been a period of 4 years and there has been no interaction between us and yourself,  your information is erased and securely disposed of.

**Deletion of data**

Your details will be deleted by us after a period of 4 years’ inactivity. If you do wish to have your data deleted before this period has elapsed, please write to the Data Protection Officer, Day Out With The Kids, 3&4 Regal Court, 6 Sovereign Road, Kings Norton Business Centre, Birmingham, B30 3FJ or email [dataprotection@dayoutwiththekids.co.uk](mailto:dataprotection@dayoutwiththekids.co.uk)

**Information requests**

Under the Data Protection Act you have the right to request a copy of the personal information Day Out With The Kids holds about you and to have any inaccuracies corrected. We require you to prove your identity with 2 pieces of approved identification.

If you are within the UK, please address requests the Data Protection Officer, Day Out With The Kids, 3&4 Regal Court, 6 Sovereign Road, Kings Norton Business Centre, Birmingham, B30 3FJ or email[dataprotection@dayoutwiththekids.co.uk](mailto:dataprotection@dayoutwiththekids.co.uk)

Methods of identification we will accept include:

  * Passport
  * Driving Licence
  * Birth certificate
  * Utility bill (from last 3 months)
  * Current vehicle registration document
  * Bank statement (from last 3 months)
  * Rent book (from last 3 months).

**Third-Party Advertising**

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.

If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having information used by these companies, please see <http://optout.networkadvertising.org/>

**Log Files**

Like many other websites, [www.dayoutwiththekids.co.uk](http://www.dayoutwiththekids.co.uk/) makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable. 

**Cookies**

A cookie is a small file that is automatically issued to your computer when you enter a website, and is stored by the browser on your computer's hard drive. Cookies identify your computer. Cookies store some basic information that helps us to identify if a user of your computer has visited the Site before.

Day Out With The Kids uses cookies which include session, permanent and third party cookies. Visit your browser’s help menu to find out more on how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie and how to disable cookies.

**Third Party Websites**

Our website contains hyperlinks to websites owned and operated by third parties. These third party websites have their own privacy policies, and are also likely to use cookies, and we therefore urge you to review them. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for the privacy practices of such third party websites and your use of such websites is at your own risk.

**Third Party Advertising Cookies**

Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on Day Out With The Kids. Google’s use cookies enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to [www.dayoutwiththekids.co.uk](http://www.dayoutwiththekids.co.uk/) and other sites on the internet. Users may view information in this at [https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/](https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/). 

Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. These third-party ad serves or ad networks use technology to show advertisements and links that appear on [www.dayoutwiththekids.co.uk](http://www.dayoutwiththekids.co.uk/) sent directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. 

Other technologies (such as cookies, Javascript or web beacons) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure effectiveness of their advertisements and/or to personalize the advertising content that you see. [www.dayoutwiththekids.co.uk](http://www.dayoutwiththekids.co.uk/) has no access to or control over these cookies. You should consult the respective privacy policies of such third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices, as well as instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. 

The [www.dayoutwiththekids.co.uk](http://www.dayoutwiththekids.co.uk/) privacy policy does to not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or websites. If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites.
